<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Arch on cat ~/differing-opinions.txt &gt; /dev/null</title>
    <link>https://www.nygaard.site/tags/arch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Arch on cat ~/differing-opinions.txt &gt; /dev/null</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 23:01:04 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.nygaard.site/tags/arch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting to Unsecured Networks</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0033-connecting-to-unsecured-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 23:01:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0033-connecting-to-unsecured-networks/</guid>
      <description>This seems to be a bit of a nightmare with Arch. I think the issue is that it is difficult to test. I typically connect to pretty good networks that have passwords and reasonable security. On vacation though, I don&amp;rsquo;t have a choice of what to connect to. I really don&amp;rsquo;t know what the advantage of WPA Enterprise is with the stupid login page. There is no way that is more secure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch Toys</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0030-arch-toys/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 22:37:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0030-arch-toys/</guid>
      <description>Before going on, make sure you meet the requirements:        General recommendations after an Arch install can be found here. I&amp;rsquo;m going to use this article to collect my list of requirements.
Okay, you have to install sudo. You also need a user. And a sudo group. use visudo to edit the sudoers file. groupadd sudo will add the sudo group. then you can gpasswd -a drone sudo to add drone to the sudo group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Arch</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0029-installing-arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 14:43:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0029-installing-arch/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to install Arch because all the cool kids do it. Really, what I wanted was more control over the system and the decisions I had to make to get it to work. In the past, I have favored speed of installation and stability of the installation because I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spend time configuring stuff that didn&amp;rsquo;t relate to what I wanted to accomplish. That basically means LTS Ubuntu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>