<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cat ~/differing-opinions.txt &gt; /dev/null</title>
    <link>https://www.nygaard.site/</link>
    <description>Recent content on cat ~/differing-opinions.txt &gt; /dev/null</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 21:59:01 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.nygaard.site/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Wordpress TLS</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0007-wordpress-tls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 21:59:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0007-wordpress-tls/</guid>
      <description>Background I needed to get a Wordpress site working for my side project. The installation process is all fine and dandy, until you want to do the right thing and enforce TLS for your site. I ran in to issues with mixed-content errors. Wordpress was requesting jQuery and some CSS files over the insecure routes to my domain.
Attempted Solutions I had a redirect block in my nginx configuration, but that did not seem to solve the issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LinkedIn Interview</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0006-linkedin-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 14:23:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0006-linkedin-interview/</guid>
      <description>I interviewed today with LinkedIn and [REDACTED]. He was intimidatingly knowledgeable and described a work environment that I really hope to join. I hope that I have the skill set necessary.
What follows are notes of the responses for my edification, not necessarily how I answered.
 Describe what happens when we type ssh shell.linkedin.com and hit enter.
  When you hit enter, your shell gets the string you entered on the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH Review</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0005-ssh-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 12:25:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0005-ssh-review/</guid>
      <description>Detail and SSH connection Symmetrical Encryption  One key can be used to encrypt messages Alice-&amp;gt;Bob but can also be used to decrypt messages Bob-&amp;gt;Alice. Anyone that holds the key, can encrypt and decrypt messages. AKA &amp;ldquo;Shared Secret&amp;rdquo; || &amp;ldquo;Secret Key&amp;rdquo; SSH uses Symmetrical encryption for the connection contrary to what most people believe (asymmetric). Asymmetric encryption is only used for authentication. Key Exchange Algorithm  Using an algorithm, the client and server can exchange data over the Asymmetrically encrypted connection to arrive at a shared secret that can be used for the Symmetrically Encrypted connection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloudflare and Hugo</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0003-cloudflare-and-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 14:34:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0003-cloudflare-and-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Hey hey! I got it to work! I&amp;rsquo;ll use this post to log what I had to do to get it to work.
Motivation I wanted a site for my personal use. I started off with a full stack deployed on AWS, but when your trial runs out, you can get hit with a pretty hefty usage.
 
That&amp;rsquo;s quite a bit of money for something that I really wanted as a note store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/about/</guid>
      <description>#GOAT Or something like that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/contact/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of ways listed in the sidebar over there.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>