<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cat ~/differing-opinions.txt &gt; /dev/null</title>
    <link>https://www.nygaard.site/</link>
    <description>Recent content on cat ~/differing-opinions.txt &gt; /dev/null</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 07:40:43 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.nygaard.site/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Explanation of Timing Attacks</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0014-explanation-of-timing-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 07:40:43 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0014-explanation-of-timing-attacks/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s say you want to know if your boss is away on vacation next week. So you call their admin and say &amp;ldquo;Can you double-check that my phone number is correct if the Boss is out next week?&amp;rdquo;.
They load up the boss&amp;rsquo; calendar to check and based on his presence next week then load up your info.
Only once done, do they take the time to remember the boss didn&amp;rsquo;t want you to know wether they are in or out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Hydra</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0013-deploying-hydra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 11:00:26 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0013-deploying-hydra/</guid>
      <description>I will document how I deploy Hydra here. We use Ansible to deploy to AWS so most of this will be high-level about how we deploy to an EC2 instance.
As of writing, the latest Hydra image is v0.10.10. I will be using that for the tutorial.
Compressed Steps (mac) I needed to get this working on mac because that is one of our development environments. The next step is to get it running on production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OAuth</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0012-oauth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 14:38:38 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0012-oauth/</guid>
      <description>Goal Implement both halves of OAuth in 2 weeks.
Background To be able to integrate with Zapier, I need to become an OAuth provider. Zapier is effectively a task runner. You can create a Zapier Application for your WebApp and give that to Zapier. Then, your users that also have Zapier accounts can go to Zapier and choose to make a &amp;lsquo;Zap&amp;rsquo; with the Zapier Application you created.
When your user decides to make a Zap that involves your application, they will have to login to your App.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Years</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0011-new-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 15:08:52 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0011-new-years/</guid>
      <description>I made a resolution that I would make public contributions on GitLab and GitHub this year. The easiest way to do that is to make blog posts because both of these repos are public (because the site is public 😜). My site is a GitLab repo with a GitHub submodule repo. The GitLab repo contains the Hugo project and the theme Blackburn. The GitHub repo is the ouput of the hugo project and exists at the conventional place you would deploy a personal GitHub page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running I3</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0010-running-i3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 12:25:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0010-running-i3/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to switch to i3, a tiling window manager. There are some things that are better, and some things that I miss. I run Ubuntu 16.04 LTS and Unity provides a lot of functionality that makes using the computer effortless. The motivation for using i3 is that, while developing, I end up tiling all my windows in separate workspaces anyways. It seems like the natural functionality of i3 better fits my use-case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Instance Resiliency</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0008-aws-instances/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 15:24:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0008-aws-instances/</guid>
      <description>I recently discovered that changing the size of and EC2 instance does not destroy the EBS volume associated with it. Let that sink in. You have a computer sitting on your desk serving your website. You realize that you&amp;rsquo;re spending too much money on electricity for this computer, so while it is running, you rip the hard drive out and put it in another computer. In 5 seconds, your website is still running.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wordpress TLS</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0007-wordpress-tls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 21:59:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0007-wordpress-tls/</guid>
      <description>Background I needed to get a Wordpress site working for my side project. The installation process is all fine and dandy, until you want to do the right thing and enforce TLS for your site. I ran in to issues with mixed-content errors. Wordpress was requesting jQuery and some CSS files over the insecure routes to my domain.
Attempted Solutions I had a redirect block in my nginx configuration, but that did not seem to solve the issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LinkedIn Interview</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0006-linkedin-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 14:23:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0006-linkedin-interview/</guid>
      <description>I interviewed today with LinkedIn and [REDACTED]. He was intimidatingly knowledgeable and described a work environment that I really hope to join. I hope that I have the skill set necessary.
What follows are notes of the responses for my edification, not necessarily how I answered.
 Describe what happens when we type ssh shell.linkedin.com and hit enter.
  When you hit enter, your shell gets the string you entered on the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH Review</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0005-ssh-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 12:25:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0005-ssh-review/</guid>
      <description>Detail and SSH connection Symmetrical Encryption  One key can be used to encrypt messages Alice-&amp;gt;Bob but can also be used to decrypt messages Bob-&amp;gt;Alice. Anyone that holds the key, can encrypt and decrypt messages. AKA &amp;ldquo;Shared Secret&amp;rdquo; || &amp;ldquo;Secret Key&amp;rdquo; SSH uses Symmetrical encryption for the connection contrary to what most people believe (asymmetric). Asymmetric encryption is only used for authentication. Key Exchange Algorithm  Using an algorithm, the client and server can exchange data over the Asymmetrically encrypted connection to arrive at a shared secret that can be used for the Symmetrically Encrypted connection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloudflare and Hugo</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0003-cloudflare-and-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 14:34:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0003-cloudflare-and-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Hey hey! I got it to work! I&amp;rsquo;ll use this post to log what I had to do to get it to work.
Motivation I wanted a site for my personal use. I started off with a full stack deployed on AWS, but when your trial runs out, you can get hit with a pretty hefty usage.
 
That&amp;rsquo;s quite a bit of money for something that I really wanted as a note store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/about/</guid>
      <description>About face.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/contact/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of ways listed in the sidebar over there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/start/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/start/</guid>
      <description>    body, html { height: 99%; display: grid; font-family: &#39;Roboto Mono&#39;, monospace; font-size: 2em; color: white; } span, div { margin: auto; }        --     var dt = new Date(); document.getElementById(&#34;datetime&#34;).innerHTML = ((&#34;0&#34;+dt.getDate()).slice(-2)) +&#34;.&#34;+ ((&#34;0&#34;+(dt.getMonth()+1)).slice(-2)) +&#34;.&#34;+ (dt.getFullYear()) +&#34; &#34;+ ((&#34;0&#34;+dt.getHours()).slice(-2)) +&#34;:&#34;+ ((&#34;0&#34;+dt.getMinutes()).slice(-2)); var body = document.getElementsByTagName(&#34;body&#34;); body[0].style.backgroundColor = &#34;#191818&#34;; function setFocusToTextBox(){ document.getElementById(&#34;searchbox&#34;).focus(); } setTimeout(setFocusToTextBox, 200)   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>