<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chicken on A Large Properly Formatted Data File</title>
    <link>https://www.nygaard.site/tags/chicken/</link>
    <description>Recent content in chicken on A Large Properly Formatted Data File</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2022. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 13:57:33 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.nygaard.site/tags/chicken/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Brine</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0038-chicken-brine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 13:57:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0038-chicken-brine/</guid>
      <description>Serious Eats is becoming my go-to for food articles. I&amp;rsquo;ll immediately check for results from them when I need a standard technique. Kenji does a great job of testing. Even things as simple as boiled eggs.
Ingredient Quantity Boneless Skinless Chicken Breast ~ 6 Breasts Kosher Salt 80g White Granulated Sugar 25g Water 2L Big Bowl 2 These measurements differ from the ones in the article because I found the resultant breasts to be too sweet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andy&#39;s Poor College Student Vietnamese Soup</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0028-andys-poor-college-student-vietnamese-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 10:00:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0028-andys-poor-college-student-vietnamese-soup/</guid>
      <description>Andy&amp;rsquo;s one of my best friends. He&amp;rsquo;s also a Vietnamese guy. He makes delicious dishes and during our time as roommates, he expanded my knowledge of ingredients. He introduced me to fish sauce and it&amp;rsquo;s role in savory dishes. Also, how it should never be left to roll around in the back of your car.
Ingredient Quantity Chicken Breast, Roasted 10 oz Butter, Salted 1 Tablespoon Onion, Chopped 1 Medium Sugar (optional) 1 Teaspoon Fish Sauce 2 Tablespoons Better than Bullion, Chicken 1 Tablespoon Okra, Sliced, Wheels 40 Pods Cilantro Handful Green Onion, Chopped Handful Water / Chicken Broth Lots Start by frying your pan ingredients together in the bottom of a heavy pot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Legs (Wing Style)</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0023-chicken-legs-wing-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 12:08:48 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0023-chicken-legs-wing-style/</guid>
      <description>I spend a lot of time thinking about protein. I get about 120g per day which is almost the minimum for my weight. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen articles recommending 1-1.5g of protein per pound of bodyweight when you&amp;rsquo;re active. Because I weigh 244lbs (today), and my goal is 200lbs, I think I should just target the goal weight quantity.
So, let&amp;rsquo;s do some chicken this week. That&amp;rsquo;ll help right? Of course, Kenji&amp;rsquo;s got me covered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Gumbo</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0019-chicken-gumbo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 10:17:53 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0019-chicken-gumbo/</guid>
      <description>This is my standard Gumbo. Alton Brown posted a recipe for inspiration, but I really just do whatever I feel like. I feel like I can deviate a bit because I don&amp;rsquo;t have a Bayou Grandma to yell at me. I&amp;rsquo;m not about to go hunting for filè powder when I&amp;rsquo;m cooking for the week.
Ingredient Quantity Flour, Wheat, All Purpose 4 Tablespoons Butter, Salted 4 Tablespoons Onion, Yellow, Chopped 1 Cup Garlic, Clove, Halved 6 Peppers, Bell, Medium, Diced 2 Celery, Diced 1 Cup Red Chili Flakes some Granulated Garlic some Cumin some Celery Salt some Black Pepper lots Smoked Paprika some Stock, Chicken 2 Cups Tomatoes, Diced, No Salt 4 Cups Okra, Wheels 4 Cups Basil Leaves 12 Make your roux first with the red ingredients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Stock</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0018-chicken-stock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 10:17:05 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0018-chicken-stock/</guid>
      <description>Basics with Babish inspired me to make some stock.
Ingredient Chicken Spines and Wings White Onions Oil Celery Carrots Leeks Parsnips Turnips Garlic (entire head) Fresh Thyme Fresh Parsley Whole Peppercorns Tasty Water Brown the red ingredients in your stock pot. Make them good and brown then deglaze with some water.
Dump in the quartered green ingredients ingredients and fill the pot with water.
BARE simmer for 4-12 hours.
Strain the boiling liquid directly in to your mouth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
