<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on cat ~/differing-opinions.txt &gt; /dev/null</title>
    <link>https://www.nygaard.site/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on cat ~/differing-opinions.txt &gt; /dev/null</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 08:49:04 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.nygaard.site/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Arch on Older Hardware</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0055-installing-arch-on-older-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 08:49:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0055-installing-arch-on-older-hardware/</guid>
      <description>First post of the New Year. Still got it in January. I moved States, bought a house, got a dog. So blogging has not been at the top of the list.
Now that I emptied my storage unit, I found my old buddy Tinman. He&amp;rsquo;s a Core i7 &amp;lsquo;server&amp;rsquo; with two GTX 480&amp;rsquo;s and 2TB of space. He&amp;rsquo;s old, but sturdy. He deserves a place of glory. And and Arch installation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions in Arch</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0048-questions-in-arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 21:28:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0048-questions-in-arch/</guid>
      <description>I notice myself asking questions about common tasks when I come back to Arch after a long time. I think that makes for a good article as it is possible others have these questions.
 I&amp;rsquo;m running out of space and that&amp;rsquo;s stupid.
 Not a question, but I&amp;rsquo;ve felt that exact sentiment.
In Arch, this is very likely the Pacman cache going crazy. Everytime you upgrade a package in Pacman, it keeps the previous version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logging with systemd</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0032-logging-with-systemd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 11:35:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0032-logging-with-systemd/</guid>
      <description>You can set your local timezone to look at the files in a sensible way. Everything is stored in UTC.
timedatectl list-timezones sudo timedatectl set-timezone America/Los_Angeles timedatectl status Local time: Wed 2018-04-18 11:34:46 PDT Universal time: Wed 2018-04-18 18:34:46 UTC RTC time: Wed 2018-04-18 18:34:45 Time zone: America/Los_Angeles (PDT, -0700) Network time on: yes NTP synchronized: yes RTC in local TZ: no You can see all the &amp;lsquo;units&amp;rsquo; that you have using the following command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch Toys</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0030-arch-toys/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 22:37:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0030-arch-toys/</guid>
      <description>Before going on, make sure you meet the requirements:        General recommendations after an Arch install can be found here. I&amp;rsquo;m going to use this article to collect my list of requirements.
Okay, you have to install sudo. You also need a user. And a sudo group. use visudo to edit the sudoers file. groupadd sudo will add the sudo group. then you can gpasswd -a drone sudo to add drone to the sudo group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Arch</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0029-installing-arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 14:43:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0029-installing-arch/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to install Arch because all the cool kids do it. Really, what I wanted was more control over the system and the decisions I had to make to get it to work. In the past, I have favored speed of installation and stability of the installation because I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spend time configuring stuff that didn&amp;rsquo;t relate to what I wanted to accomplish. That basically means LTS Ubuntu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running I3</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0010-running-i3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 12:25:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0010-running-i3/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to switch to i3, a tiling window manager. There are some things that are better, and some things that I miss. I run Ubuntu 16.04 LTS and Unity provides a lot of functionality that makes using the computer effortless. The motivation for using i3 is that, while developing, I end up tiling all my windows in separate workspaces anyways. It seems like the natural functionality of i3 better fits my use-case.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>