<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on cat ~/differing-opinions.txt &gt; /dev/null</title>
    <link>https://www.nygaard.site/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on cat ~/differing-opinions.txt &gt; /dev/null</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 14:50:08 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.nygaard.site/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Keybase Filesystem</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0031-keybase-filesystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 14:50:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0031-keybase-filesystem/</guid>
      <description>Keybase has a great feature called kbfs. You get 10 Gigs of storage forever. They say that it will be free going forward, and I would like to believe them because I don&amp;rsquo;t think Keybase will ever really be popular. I would love to eat those words.
They mention that you should not expect your files to be resilient; this is an Alpha service, so there is no guarantee of safety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch Toys</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0030-arch-toys/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 22:37:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0030-arch-toys/</guid>
      <description>Before going on, make sure you meet the requirements:        General recommendations after an Arch install can be found here. I&amp;rsquo;m going to use this article to collect my list of requirements.
Okay, you have to install sudo. You also need a user. And a sudo group. use visudo to edit the sudoers file. groupadd sudo will add the sudo group. then you can gpasswd -a drone sudo to add drone to the sudo group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Arch</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0029-installing-arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 14:43:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0029-installing-arch/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to install Arch because all the cool kids do it. Really, what I wanted was more control over the system and the decisions I had to make to get it to work. In the past, I have favored speed of installation and stability of the installation because I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spend time configuring stuff that didn&amp;rsquo;t relate to what I wanted to accomplish. That basically means LTS Ubuntu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running I3</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0010-running-i3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 12:25:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0010-running-i3/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to switch to i3, a tiling window manager. There are some things that are better, and some things that I miss. I run Ubuntu 16.04 LTS and Unity provides a lot of functionality that makes using the computer effortless. The motivation for using i3 is that, while developing, I end up tiling all my windows in separate workspaces anyways. It seems like the natural functionality of i3 better fits my use-case.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>