<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>stew on cat ~/differing-opinions.txt &gt; /dev/null</title>
    <link>https://www.nygaard.site/tags/stew/</link>
    <description>Recent content in stew on cat ~/differing-opinions.txt &gt; /dev/null</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2022. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 08:29:52 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.nygaard.site/tags/stew/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beef Stew</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0056-beef-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 08:29:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0056-beef-stew/</guid>
      <description>This is just a classic. I would hesitate to call this a recipe and really more of a &amp;lsquo;method&amp;rsquo;. This is really about getting as much beef in your mouth as you can and extending that experience with potatoes and carrots.
Ingredient Quantity Butter 4 Tablespoons Beef, Chuck 4lbs whole Baking Powder 1 Tablespoon, For Dusting Onion, White 1 Large Celery 3 Large Stalks Garlic 1 Head, All Cloves Carrots 2 Large Carrots 3 Large Little Potatoes 20 Small Bay Leaves 4 Fresh Soy Sauce 1/4 Cup Apple Cider Vinegar 2 Tablespoons Thyme Lots of sprigs Chipotle Chiles 2 Tomato Paste 2 Tablespoons Bone Broth 1 Quart Wine 1 Cup Fire Roasted Canned Diced Tomatoes 2 14oz Cans Instant Pot 1 Procedure Firstly, let your beef come to room temperature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Gumbo</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0019-chicken-gumbo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 10:17:53 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0019-chicken-gumbo/</guid>
      <description>This is my standard Gumbo. Alton Brown posted a recipe for inspiration, but I really just do whatever I feel like. I feel like I can deviate a bit because I don&amp;rsquo;t have a Bayou Grandma to yell at me. I&amp;rsquo;m not about to go hunting for filè powder when I&amp;rsquo;m cooking for the week.
Ingredient Quantity Flour, Wheat, All Purpose 4 Tablespoons Butter, Salted 4 Tablespoons Onion, Yellow, Chopped 1 Cup Garlic, Clove, Halved 6 Peppers, Bell, Medium, Diced 2 Celery, Diced 1 Cup Red Chili Flakes some Granulated Garlic some Cumin some Celery Salt some Black Pepper lots Smoked Paprika some Stock, Chicken 2 Cups Tomatoes, Diced, No Salt 4 Cups Okra, Wheels 4 Cups Basil Leaves 12 Make your roux first with the red ingredients.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
