<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on cat ~/differing-opinions.txt &gt; /dev/null</title>
    <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on cat ~/differing-opinions.txt &gt; /dev/null</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 21:35:45 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.nygaard.site/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vi Daily Driver</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0059-vi-daily-driver/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 21:35:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0059-vi-daily-driver/</guid>
      <description>Motivation It would be really cool to have Neovim work like Foam and get away from VSCode. I was partially inspired by Cool desktops don’t change 😎. The article worried me about the collapse of Atom and what that might mean for VSCode.
Caveats I used Neovim and it is aliased to vi on my system. I&amp;rsquo;m not confusing the various projects (Neovim, Vim, vi, ed). vi is just very satisfying to type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pilot Butte</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0058-pilot-butte/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 14:03:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0058-pilot-butte/</guid>
      <description>I was looking on the map for something to do and I found a fucking Golden Spiral in the middle of the city. Done deal. Let&amp;rsquo;s walk there.
Pilot Butte                 I like the look of the track generated for walking up Pilot Butte. It&amp;rsquo;s an old Cinder Cone and it is like a perfect pimple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming File Uploads to HDFS</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0057-streaming-file-uploads-to-hdfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 13:56:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0057-streaming-file-uploads-to-hdfs/</guid>
      <description>I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a good source for this information in one place, that&amp;rsquo;s a dead giveaway that I should be writing an article.
Some meta discussion, it looks like I&amp;rsquo;ve been away a while and that&amp;rsquo;s because I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a organizing my cookbook. I used to just post recipes here (in the &amp;lsquo;before times&amp;rsquo;) but I&amp;rsquo;ve found that I hate using a digital device when I need to reference a recipe in the heat of the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beef Stew</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0056-beef-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 08:29:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0056-beef-stew/</guid>
      <description>This is just a classic. I would hesitate to call this a recipe and really more of a &amp;lsquo;method&amp;rsquo;. This is really about getting as much beef in your mouth as you can and extending that experience with potatoes and carrots.
 Ingredient Quantity     Butter    4 Tablespoons      Beef, Chuck    4lbs whole      Baking Powder    1 Tablespoon, For Dusting      Onion, White    1 Large      Celery    3 Large Stalks      Garlic    1 Head, All Cloves      Carrots    2 Large      Carrots    3 Large      Little Potatoes    20 Small      Bay Leaves    4 Fresh      Soy Sauce    1/4 Cup      Apple Cider Vinegar    2 Tablespoons      Thyme    Lots of sprigs      Chipotle Chiles    2      Tomato Paste    2 Tablespoons      Bone Broth    1 Quart      Wine    1 Cup      Fire Roasted Canned Diced Tomatoes    2 14oz Cans      Instant Pot    1      Procedure Firstly, let your beef come to room temperature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Arch on Older Hardware</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0055-installing-arch-on-older-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 08:49:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0055-installing-arch-on-older-hardware/</guid>
      <description>First post of the New Year. Still got it in January. I moved States, bought a house, got a dog. So blogging has not been at the top of the list.
Now that I emptied my storage unit, I found my old buddy Tinman. He&amp;rsquo;s a Core i7 &amp;lsquo;server&amp;rsquo; with two GTX 480&amp;rsquo;s and 2TB of space. He&amp;rsquo;s old, but sturdy. He deserves a place of glory. And and Arch installation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engagement Hike</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0053-engagement-hike/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 13:14:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0053-engagement-hike/</guid>
      <description>I proposed to my wife in Kauai at the Waimea Canyon Lookout. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have picked a better spot. Actually, I did. When we did the hike I picked the first spot you see here. You can see in the Google Earth picture the more teal trace as it curve along the rim. These two pictures are of that first spot. The &amp;lsquo;real&amp;rsquo; spot.
       However, in the following two, you can see the &amp;lsquo;real real&amp;rsquo; spot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convict Lake Loop</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0052-convict-lake-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 09:45:14 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0052-convict-lake-loop/</guid>
      <description>This is Convict Lake. I grew coming here to hike and camp. My two fondest birthday celebrations have been at this lake. The first with my parents for my 12th birthday. The second with my parents and now wife for my 35th birthday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extending GPG Expiry</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0051-extending-gpg-expiry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 21:36:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0051-extending-gpg-expiry/</guid>
      <description>If you followed my last article on this subject, you have a GPG setup without the master private key on your computer. You also put an expiration date on that key. When your key expires, it can no longer be used to encrypt data for you. It can however still decrypt messages from prior to the expiry date. This does not help in the situation where your private key is compromised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jalapeño Poppers</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0050-jalapeno-poppers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 12:19:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0050-jalapeno-poppers/</guid>
      <description>Ash has been wanting these for 2 months. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t say no when we were going to be using the Traeger anyways.
 Ingredient Quantity     Jalapeños    18 Medium      Thin-Cut Bacon    1 Pack      Cream Cheese    8-10 Oz (room temperature)      Colby Jack    4 Oz      Chili Powder    1 tsp      Granulated Garlic    1 tsp      Salt    1 tsp      Scallions    2 minced      Procedure Split the jalapeños lengthwise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ribs</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0049-ribs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 12:00:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0049-ribs/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s better than a BBQ on a National Holiday?
I used the Traeger for some St. Louis cut ribs. This recipe was crazy simple. Like shamefully simple. Mostly I just want to get in the habit of updating my blog, so this is what you get.
 Ingredient Quantity     St. Louis Ribs    2 Racks      Favorite Rub    Lots      Texas Blend Traeger Pellets    At least 2 hoppers worth      Oh yeah, you&amp;rsquo;ll need a Traeger too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions in Arch</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0048-questions-in-arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 21:28:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0048-questions-in-arch/</guid>
      <description>I notice myself asking questions about common tasks when I come back to Arch after a long time. I think that makes for a good article as it is possible others have these questions.
 I&amp;rsquo;m running out of space and that&amp;rsquo;s stupid.
 Not a question, but I&amp;rsquo;ve felt that exact sentiment.
In Arch, this is very likely the Pacman cache going crazy. Every time you upgrade a package in Pacman, it keeps the previous version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bone Broth</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0046-bone-broth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 22:10:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0046-bone-broth/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t really like the distinction between &amp;lsquo;bone broth&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;stock&amp;rsquo; because they&amp;rsquo;re the same thing if done right. The distinction is useful because the product that is called stock in a grocery store is very different. Useful, but different.
Bone broth is gelatinous at fridge temperature. This is because you cook down the bones and connective tissue over a long period of time. Collagen is converted to gelatin and you get meat/bone jello.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Post Please Ignore</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0044-test-post-please-ignore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 21:08:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0044-test-post-please-ignore/</guid>
      <description>Shortcodes Hugo has a bunch of shortcodes. This is just a post of me testing them. Nothing to see here.
gist  Figure  Cloud Development   #!/bin/bash  echo gooby &amp;lt;section id=&amp;#34;main&amp;#34;&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;h1 id=&amp;#34;title&amp;#34;&amp;gt;{{ .Title }}&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;  {{ range .Pages }}  {{ .Render &amp;#34;summary&amp;#34;}}  {{ end }}  &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/section&amp;gt; Tweet Hugo 0.24 Released: Big archetype update + @Netlify _redirects etc. file supporthttps://t.co/X94FmYDEZJ #gohugo #golang @spf13 @bepsays</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JetBrains and GPG</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0042-jetbrains-and-gpg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 13:17:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0042-jetbrains-and-gpg/</guid>
      <description>I encountered some issues running WebStorm and I think I finally solved them. This was an annoying bug that was a mix of WebStorm and OSX behavior that I didn&amp;rsquo;t ask for.
TODO: Pinentry Image
This is the prompt that you get on OSX running Pinentry. I was getting this randomly all throughout the day just running JetBrains products. That&amp;rsquo;s really annoying. You can see that WebStorm is trying to run git-upload-pack when I get the Pinentry prompt, and that is what triggered it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPG for SSH</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0041-gpg-for-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 13:08:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0041-gpg-for-ssh/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m using the gpg-agent in place of the ssh-agent. I think this is a very interesting use because it eliminates the need for me to store my ssh key as a flat file:
ssh-add -l 4096 SHA256:rsOIZD3XP+Tvj+l5xrbRnxgvdg2qKL5agAxzPLT5rao (none) (RSA) 2048 SHA256:U6ETCKbdPbvgPMSjePS0jrGR3yMdhF9NC6MUHItynJc /Users/admin/.ssh/splice-dcos.pem (RSA) ... You can see here that the top key is one that is generated by GPG and not associated with any particular file. That being said, I still have to use SSH keys that are given to me for work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airgapped GPG</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0039-airgapped-gpg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 08:16:14 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0039-airgapped-gpg/</guid>
      <description>Airgapped Media Arch BBS SuperUser
Format I&amp;rsquo;ll save you the explanation of what GPG is. First thing I needed was a USB stick that would be compatible with Arch and MacOS. This fight is always interesting and I would rank the better operating system as the one that can compromise on the filesystem. Naturally, insert the USB stick in the MacOS and format it as a Journaled HFS+ partition because we can install the driver on Arch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Brine</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0038-chicken-brine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 13:57:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0038-chicken-brine/</guid>
      <description>Serious Eats is becoming my go-to for food articles. I&amp;rsquo;ll immediately check for results from them when I need a standard technique. Kenji does a great job of testing. Even things as simple as boiled eggs.
 Ingredient Quantity     Boneless Skinless Chicken Breast    ~ 6 Breasts      Kosher Salt    80g      White Granulated Sugar    25g      Water    2L      Big Bowl    2      These measurements differ from the ones in the article because I found the resultant breasts to be too sweet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch VPN</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0037-arch-vpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 12:38:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0037-arch-vpn/</guid>
      <description>I have trouble sometimes navigating network connectivity using Arch. The OS doesn&amp;rsquo;t really have an issue getting out to networks, I just seem to not remember what to do in a time of need. Unfortunately, it is usually the first thing you need to do to begin the problem solving process.
It is not lost on me that I am posting this article on the Internet. You&amp;rsquo;ll find it after you get in to trouble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quince</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0036-quince/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 10:31:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0036-quince/</guid>
      <description>We went to Quince. It was awesome. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a review, I&amp;rsquo;m not qualified for that. If you can go, you should go. Take more pictures than I did.
Menu and Pairings English Peas Sicilian Pistachio, Horseradish
Wine: F.X. Pichler, Grüner Veltliner, Federspiel, &amp;ldquo;Loibenberg Frauenweigarten&amp;rdquo;, Wachau, Austria 2015
Tsar Nicoulai Caviar Avocado, Ruby Beet, Sorrel
Wine: Krug, &amp;ldquo;Grand Cuvée 166 Ème Édition,&amp;rdquo; Champagne, France, MV
Squid Zucchini, Pine Nut, Saffron</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel Kitchen Checklist</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0035-travel-kitchen-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 17:48:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0035-travel-kitchen-checklist/</guid>
      <description>I got a subscription to Bon Appétit recently because I spent some money at Sur la Table. I really like the magazine, especially the fact that they concentrate all the featured recipes at the back of the issue. That&amp;rsquo;s nice because you can just cut stuff out there.
They had a feature about what to pack if you have to go cook somewhere. I liked the list and I want to keep it for myself on the public internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting to Unsecured Networks</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0033-connecting-to-unsecured-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 23:01:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0033-connecting-to-unsecured-networks/</guid>
      <description>This seems to be a bit of a nightmare with Arch. I think the issue is that it is difficult to test. I typically connect to pretty good networks that have passwords and reasonable security. On vacation though, I don&amp;rsquo;t have a choice of what to connect to. I really don&amp;rsquo;t know what the advantage of WPA Enterprise is with the stupid login page. There is no way that is more secure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logging with systemd</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0032-logging-with-systemd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 11:35:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0032-logging-with-systemd/</guid>
      <description>You can set your local timezone to look at the files in a sensible way. Everything is stored in UTC.
timedatectl list-timezones sudo timedatectl set-timezone America/Los_Angeles timedatectl status  Local time: Wed 2018-04-18 11:34:46 PDT  Universal time: Wed 2018-04-18 18:34:46 UTC  RTC time: Wed 2018-04-18 18:34:45  Time zone: America/Los_Angeles (PDT, -0700)  Network time on: yes NTP synchronized: yes  RTC in local TZ: no You can see all the &amp;lsquo;units&amp;rsquo; that you have using the following command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch Toys</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0030-arch-toys/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 22:37:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0030-arch-toys/</guid>
      <description>Before going on, make sure you meet the requirements:
       General recommendations after an Arch install can be found here. I&amp;rsquo;m going to use this article to collect my list of requirements.
Okay, you have to install sudo. You also need a user. And a sudo group. Use visudo to edit the sudoers file. groupadd sudo will add the sudo group. Then you can gpasswd -a drone sudo to add drone to the sudo group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Arch</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0029-installing-arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 14:43:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0029-installing-arch/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to install Arch because all the cool kids do it. Really, what I wanted was more control over the system and the decisions I had to make to get it to work. In the past, I have favored speed of installation and stability of the installation because I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spend time configuring stuff that didn&amp;rsquo;t relate to what I wanted to accomplish. That basically means LTS Ubuntu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andy&#39;s Poor College Student Vietnamese Soup</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0028-andys-poor-college-student-vietnamese-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 10:00:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0028-andys-poor-college-student-vietnamese-soup/</guid>
      <description>Andy&amp;rsquo;s one of my best friends. He&amp;rsquo;s also a Vietnamese guy. He makes delicious dishes and during our time as roommates, he expanded my knowledge of ingredients. He introduced me to fish sauce and it&amp;rsquo;s role in savory dishes. Also, how it should never be left to roll around in the back of your car.
 Ingredient Quantity     Chicken Breast, Roasted    10 oz      Butter, Salted    1 Tablespoon      Onion, Chopped    1 Medium      Sugar (optional)    1 Teaspoon      Fish Sauce    2 Tablespoons      Better than Bullion, Chicken    1 Tablespoon      Okra, Sliced, Wheels    40 Pods      Cilantro    Handful      Green Onion, Chopped    Handful      Water / Chicken Broth    Lots      Start by frying your pan ingredients together in the bottom of a heavy pot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World on Android</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0027-hello-world-on-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 13:02:13 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0027-hello-world-on-android/</guid>
      <description>Motivation I wanted to get my environment ready for Android development. It was pretty straightforward on the Mac, I can see it being more of a headache on other platforms.
Procedure Firstly, download Android Studio. It is pretty amazing that they&amp;rsquo;ve wrapped everything you need in a free IDE. There&amp;rsquo;s a ton of shit for Java projects that I&amp;rsquo;d rather not think about.
I&amp;rsquo;m using this training course. Open it in another tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roasted Bird&#39;s Eye Chili Powder</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0025-roasted-birds-eye-chili-powder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 08:09:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0025-roasted-birds-eye-chili-powder/</guid>
      <description>Fuck yo tongue.
 Ingredient Quantity     Chilies    Tub `O      Break the ends off the chilies and throw away any mushy or moldy ones. Lovingly slice them in half lengthwise. You could take the time to seed them, but that kinda defeats the purpose of making your own ridiculously hot crushed peppers.
Use gloves if you like to touch yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overnight Pizza Dough</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0024-overnight-pizza-dough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 16:52:35 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0024-overnight-pizza-dough/</guid>
      <description>Basics with Babish did pizza dough this week. I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for Sunday all week because of that.
He mentions that the recipe is Jim Lahey&amp;rsquo;s overnight pizza dough. The recipe looks super simple and I love the fact that everything is listed in grams. Baking is science and that&amp;rsquo;s usually why I don&amp;rsquo;t do it. I don&amp;rsquo;t really like following directions in the kitchen, but I can make an exception for pizza.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Legs (Wing Style)</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0023-chicken-legs-wing-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 12:08:48 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0023-chicken-legs-wing-style/</guid>
      <description>I spend a lot of time thinking about protein. I get about 120g per day which is almost the minimum for my weight. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen articles recommending 1-1.5g of protein per pound of bodyweight when you&amp;rsquo;re active. Because I weigh 244lbs (today), and my goal is 200lbs, I think I should just target the goal weight quantity.
So, let&amp;rsquo;s do some chicken this week. That&amp;rsquo;ll help right? Of course, Kenji&amp;rsquo;s got me covered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mini Breakfast Casseroles</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0022-mini-breakfast-casseroles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 12:07:08 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0022-mini-breakfast-casseroles/</guid>
      <description>That mini-muffin pan is one of the best weight-loss buys I&amp;rsquo;ve made. 24 little slots to fill with goodness. I haven&amp;rsquo;t ever used it for muffins though. Because muffins suck. Meatballs win every time.
These things are fun too. Some eggs and some low cal sausage and you have little breakfast party bites that run about 29 calories a pop.
Go get these things:
 Ingredient Quantity     Eggs    4      Egg Whites    4      Red Bell Pepper    1      Mushrooms    11      Green Onions    6ish?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roasted Tomatillo Salsa</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0021-roasted-tomatillo-salsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 11:19:57 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0021-roasted-tomatillo-salsa/</guid>
      <description>Ingredient Quantity     Tomatillos    6      Jalapeños    3      Garlic    5 Cloves      Onion    1/2 Large      Pork Juice    Whatever you got      This salsa comes from the desire to use the rendered pork juices from the carnitas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oven Carnitas</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0020-oven-carnitas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 11:19:44 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0020-oven-carnitas/</guid>
      <description>Kenji seems to have superpowers. I like everything I&amp;rsquo;ve made with his guidance, and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that this is no exception. I love me some carnitas and I think that trimming off the fat will fit well in my diet.
I found 16 lbs of Pork Butt (Shoulder) at Costco. Only when I got home did I realize that it might have been a bit of overkill. I put half in the freezer for some other adventure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Gumbo</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0019-chicken-gumbo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 10:17:53 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0019-chicken-gumbo/</guid>
      <description>This is my standard Gumbo. Alton Brown posted a recipe for inspiration, but I really just do whatever I feel like. I feel like I can deviate a bit because I don&amp;rsquo;t have a Bayou Grandma to yell at me. I&amp;rsquo;m not about to go hunting for filè powder when I&amp;rsquo;m cooking for the week.
 Ingredient Quantity     Flour, Wheat, All Purpose    4 Tablespoons      Butter, Salted    4 Tablespoons      Onion, Yellow, Chopped    1 Cup      Garlic, Clove, Halved    6      Peppers, Bell, Medium, Diced    2      Celery, Diced    1 Cup      Red Chili Flakes    some      Granulated Garlic    some      Cumin    some      Celery Salt    some      Black Pepper    lots      Smoked Paprika    some      Stock, Chicken    2 Cups      Tomatoes, Diced, No Salt    4 Cups      Okra, Wheels    4 Cups      Basil Leaves    12      Make your roux first with the red ingredients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Stock</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0018-chicken-stock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 10:17:05 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0018-chicken-stock/</guid>
      <description>Basics with Babish inspired me to make some stock.
 Ingredient     Chicken Spines and Wings      White Onions      Oil      Celery      Carrots      Leeks      Parsnips      Turnips      Garlic (entire head)      Fresh Thyme      Fresh Parsley      Whole Peppercorns      Tasty Water      Brown the red ingredients in your stock pot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expose OAuth Endpoints</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0017-expose-oauth-endpoints/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 14:46:14 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0017-expose-oauth-endpoints/</guid>
      <description>Zapier Zapier gives me a list of things that I will need to configure for the zapier app to be able to communicate with my app vi OAuth. I think this is a good way to call out the routes I need to build.
 Authentication Type  OAuth V2 w/refresh   Client ID  AKA &amp;ldquo;Consumer Key&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;API Key&amp;rdquo; zapier   Client Secret  AKA &amp;ldquo;Consumer Secret&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;API Secret&amp;rdquo; asdjhalsgdhgaposdigu (some string)   Authorization URL  For now I will list what I see the consent app presenting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Hydra on a Mac for Testing</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0016-run-hydra-on-a-mac-for-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 09:45:26 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0016-run-hydra-on-a-mac-for-testing/</guid>
      <description>These are the steps (both up and down) to get get the Hydra Consent Flow example working locally on a Mac.
Infrastructure Create Database Up
echo &amp;#34;create database hydra&amp;#34; | mysql -uroot -proot Down
echo &amp;#34;drop database hydra&amp;#34; | mysql -uroot -proot Export Stuff Up
export DATABASE_URL=mysql://root:root@tcp(docker.for.mac.localhost:3306)/hydra?parseTime=true export SYSTEM_SECRET=yJFLIU44byGmmKLwJHvrIamNknAmSQR27C Down
Nothing. Migrations Up
docker run -it --rm \  oryd/hydra:v0.10.10 \  migrate sql $DATABASE_URL Down
Nothing. Run Hydra Container Up</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Screenshot Directly to Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0015-take-screenshot-directly-to-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 12:17:32 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0015-take-screenshot-directly-to-preview/</guid>
      <description>Okay this is my first foray in to AppleScript, and I have to say that I don&amp;rsquo;t hate it. I wanted a way to take screenshots directly in to Preview on my Mac.
Turns out that the screenshot utility is available on the command line:
&amp;gt; screencapture -h screencapture: illegal option -- h usage: screencapture [-icMPmwsWxSCUtoa] [files]  -c force screen capture to go to the clipboard  -b capture Touch Bar - non-interactive modes only .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explanation of Timing Attacks</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0014-explanation-of-timing-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 07:40:43 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0014-explanation-of-timing-attacks/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s say you want to know if your boss is away on vacation next week. So you call their admin and say &amp;ldquo;Can you double-check that my phone number is correct if the Boss is out next week?&amp;rdquo;.
  They load up the boss&amp;rsquo; calendar to check and based on his presence next week then load up your info.
  Only once done, do they take the time to remember the boss didn&amp;rsquo;t want you to know wether they are in or out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zapier and the OAuth2.0 Mountain</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0013-deploying-hydra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 11:00:26 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0013-deploying-hydra/</guid>
      <description>Background Zapier is effectively a task runner. Integrating with them would put FlowMojo in a marketplace of other productivity applications. I think it will really fuel adoption. To get in the door with Zapier, I need to become an OAuth provider.
You can create a Zapier Application for your WebApp and give that to Zapier. Then, your users that also have Zapier accounts can go to Zapier and choose to make a &amp;lsquo;Zap&amp;rsquo; with the Zapier Application you created.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Years</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0011-new-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 15:08:52 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0011-new-years/</guid>
      <description>I made a resolution that I would make public contributions on GitLab and GitHub this year. The easiest way to do that is to make blog posts because both of these repos are public (because the site is public 😜). My site is a GitLab repo with a GitHub submodule repo. The GitLab repo contains the Hugo project and the theme Blackburn. The GitHub repo is the output of the hugo project and exists at the conventional place you would deploy a personal GitHub page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running I3</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0010-running-i3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 12:25:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0010-running-i3/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to switch to i3, a tiling window manager. There are some things that are better, and some things that I miss. I run Ubuntu 16.04 LTS and Unity provides a lot of functionality that makes using the computer effortless. The motivation for using i3 is that, while developing, I end up tiling all my windows in separate workspaces anyways. It seems like the natural functionality of i3 better fits my use-case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Instance Resiliency</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0008-aws-instances/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 15:24:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0008-aws-instances/</guid>
      <description>I recently discovered that changing the size of and EC2 instance does not destroy the EBS volume associated with it. Let that sink in. You have a computer sitting on your desk serving your website. You realize that you&amp;rsquo;re spending too much money on electricity for this computer, so while it is running, you rip the hard drive out and put it in another computer. In 5 seconds, your website is still running.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wordpress TLS</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0007-wordpress-tls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 21:59:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0007-wordpress-tls/</guid>
      <description>Background I needed to get a Wordpress site working for my side project. The installation process is all fine and dandy, until you want to do the right thing and enforce TLS for your site. I ran in to issues with mixed-content errors. Wordpress was requesting jQuery and some CSS files over the insecure routes to my domain.
Attempted Solutions I had a redirect block in my nginx configuration, but that did not seem to solve the issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LinkedIn Interview</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0006-linkedin-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 14:23:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0006-linkedin-interview/</guid>
      <description>I interviewed today with LinkedIn and [REDACTED]. He was intimidatingly knowledgeable and described a work environment that I really hope to join. I hope that I have the skill set necessary.
What follows are notes of the responses for my edification, not necessarily how I answered.
 Describe what happens when we type ssh shell.linkedin.com and hit enter.
  When you hit enter, your shell gets the string you entered on the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH Review</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0005-ssh-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 12:25:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0005-ssh-review/</guid>
      <description>Detail and SSH connection Symmetrical Encryption  One key can be used to encrypt messages Alice-&amp;gt;Bob but can also be used to decrypt messages Bob-&amp;gt;Alice. Anyone that holds the key, can encrypt and decrypt messages. AKA &amp;ldquo;Shared Secret&amp;rdquo; || &amp;ldquo;Secret Key&amp;rdquo; SSH uses Symmetrical encryption for the connection contrary to what most people believe (asymmetric). Asymmetric encryption is only used for authentication. Key Exchange Algorithm  Using an algorithm, the client and server can exchange data over the Asymmetrically encrypted connection to arrive at a shared secret that can be used for the Symmetrically Encrypted connection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloudflare and Hugo</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0003-cloudflare-and-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 14:34:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0003-cloudflare-and-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Hey hey! I got it to work! I&amp;rsquo;ll use this post to log what I had to do to get it to work.
Motivation I wanted a site for my personal use. I started off with a full stack deployed on AWS, but when your trial runs out, you can get hit with a pretty hefty usage.
 
That&amp;rsquo;s quite a bit of money for something that I really wanted as a note store.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
