<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>beef on cat ~/differing-opinions.txt &gt; /dev/null</title>
    <link>https://www.nygaard.site/tags/beef/</link>
    <description>Recent content in beef on cat ~/differing-opinions.txt &gt; /dev/null</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2022. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 08:29:52 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.nygaard.site/tags/beef/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beef Stew</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0056-beef-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 08:29:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0056-beef-stew/</guid>
      <description>This is just a classic. I would hesitate to call this a recipe and really more of a &amp;lsquo;method&amp;rsquo;. This is really about getting as much beef in your mouth as you can and extending that experience with potatoes and carrots.
Ingredient Quantity Butter 4 Tablespoons Beef, Chuck 4lbs whole Baking Powder 1 Tablespoon, For Dusting Onion, White 1 Large Celery 3 Large Stalks Garlic 1 Head, All Cloves Carrots 2 Large Carrots 3 Large Little Potatoes 20 Small Bay Leaves 4 Fresh Soy Sauce 1/4 Cup Apple Cider Vinegar 2 Tablespoons Thyme Lots of sprigs Chipotle Chiles 2 Tomato Paste 2 Tablespoons Bone Broth 1 Quart Wine 1 Cup Fire Roasted Canned Diced Tomatoes 2 14oz Cans Instant Pot 1 Procedure Firstly, let your beef come to room temperature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bone Broth</title>
      <link>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0046-bone-broth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 22:10:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nygaard.site/post/0046-bone-broth/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t really like the distinction between &amp;lsquo;bone broth&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;stock&amp;rsquo; because they&amp;rsquo;re the same thing if done right. The distinction is useful because the product that is called stock in a grocery store is very different. Useful, but different.
Bone broth is gelatinous at fridge temperature. This is because you cook down the bones and connective tissue over a long period of time. Collagen is converted to gelatin and you get meat/bone jello.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
